VALLUM OY

Eero Siljander

Power BI and Azure Data Engineer / Data Scientist



Contact Info

Address:

c/o Vallum Oy Kampinkuja 2 00100 Helsinki

Mobile:

+358 400264828

Email:

timo.valli@vallum.fi

Language Skills

Finnish – mother's tongue English – excellent Swedish – fair

Education

IPMA D, 2015 Licenciate of Econometrics, 2005 ja Master, 2002, University of Helsinki

Summary

Eero Siljander has long experience (since 2015) as Power BI and Azure Data Engineer / Data Scientist in various projects. He is Microsoft certified Azure Administrator Associate including Azure AI Fundamentals, Azure Data Fundamentals and Azure Fundamentals. He is also Microsoft Certified in Security, Compliance and Identity Fundamentals.

Most recently in Autumn 2022 he has worked as a Data Analyst at City of Helsinki, before that he worked as a Cloud Solution Architect in Sandvik Group and Valmet using PowerBI, PowerQuery and DAX to build visualization dashboards and reports. He has worked as an IT specialist at National Supervisory Authority for Wellbeing and Health (Valvira) where he has used PowerBI and PowerQuery in the Information Management system implementation project.

Eero has excellent knowledge of Finnish and English languages and fair command in Swedish language. He is good team player and convincing in his interactions. He holds a Licentiate degree in Econometrics. Eero has IPMA D project work certificate and has attended plenty of technology certifications and courses.

Relevant Experience

Data Analyst (City of Helsinki), 06/2022 – 9/2022 Q Factory Oy, Helsinki

- PowerBI, PowerQuery, DAX visualizations Education Data and Azure Database
- Time Series Data, Drilling Dashboard, Star Data Model

Consultant (Finnish Insurance Centre), 03/2022 – 07/2022 Softico Oy, Helsinki

Cloud Solution Architect (Sandvik Group, Valmet), 10/2021 – 02/2022 Etteplan Oy, Helsinki

- PowerBI, PowerBI, DAX visualizations of Machinery R&D
 Process Data and Azure Database
- Complex Data Model, Time Series / Event Data
- PowerBI, PowerBI, DAX visualizations of Customer Satisfaction Data and Azure Database
- Star Data Model, Statistical Functions

Consultant, 01/2020 - 04/2020 CGI Finland Oy, Helsinki

IT Specialist, 01/2019 - 05/2019

National Supervisory Authority for Wellbeing and Health, Helsinki

- PowerBI, PoweQuery, DAX visualizations of Health data and Azure Database
- Time Series Data, Star Data Model

Solutions Consultant, 07/2018 - 12/2018 Tieto Oyj, Helsinki

Health Economist, 12/2009 - 2/2015

National Supervisory Authority for Wellbeing and Health, Helsinki